ARAF AL-JAMI

 $arafaljami1331@gmail.com \diamond araf.aljami.me \diamond +8801755045141$

SUMMARY

Around 2 years of working experience as a software engineer, with a strong pursuit of problem solving. Hands on experience in building enterprise applications and maintaining best practices with OOD. Followed SOLID principles and design patterns to write clean, maintainable and adaptive code.

SKILLS

Languages: C#, Javascript, Typescript, C/C++

Specialties: .NET, .NET Core, Web API, Git, S2Geometry, Agile Scrum methodology, Angular, AngularJS.

Database and messaging: MongoDB, MySQL, RabbitMQ, Mqtt, Azure Service Bus.

EXPERIENCE

Shohoj Limited, Dhaka

Feb 2020 - Present

Software Engineer, Platform

Shohoz is a super app that aims to simplify and resolve day to day needs while making life easier and efficient. It has platforms like ride sharing, food delivery, bus and launch ticket booking, truck booking and many more are coming. Shohoz super app is downloaded more than 5M times and is a proud server of more than 150M people.

- · Used Dotnet Core technologies to develope REST Api.
- · Used S2Geometry, Redis to refine Nearest provider search, improving perfomance up to 15 times.
- · Used **TDD**, **DDD** to write robust, adaptable code.

SELISE rockin' software, Dhaka

Nov 2018 - Jan 2020

 $Software\ Engineer$

- · Used Angular, AngularJS to develope Single Page Applications
- · Used Dotnet Core technologies to develope REST Api.
- · Worked on multiple projects and implemented business requirements for Selise Auditing and Certification Platform.

Problem Setter and Judge at NSU Cybernauts National Programming Contest 2019

· Set problem and written alternate solution. [link]

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

Onsite Competitive Programming Contests

September 2014 - Present

- \cdot 10th place (4th place University wise) out of **150** teams, at IUBAT ACM NCPC 2018. [link]
- · 16th place (8th place University wise) out of **120** teams, at MIST IUPC 2019

Online Competitive Programming Contests

September 2014 - Present

- · Active participant in online coding challenges on sites such as **TopCoder**, **Codeforces**.
- · Achieved Maximum Rating of 1982 (top 4%) in Codeforces. Handle: CLown1331. [link]
- · Achieved Maximum Rating of 1469 (Division 1) in TopCoder. Handle: CLown1331. [link]
- · Solved around 2700 problems in various online judges. [link]

EDUCATION

Leading University, Sylhet

September 2014 - April 2019